MUHAMMED OSINUBI ADEBANJO

FRONTEND | JAVASCRIPT DEVELOPER

(+234) 805-1490-908 || (+234) 9024986943

PORTFOLIO: https://mdindahouse.github.io/Portfolio/

GITHUB: https://github.com/MDindahouse

SUMMARY

I'm Front-end || JavaScript Developer with 4 years of experience leveraging HTML, CSS and JAVASCRIPT, JS FRAMEWORKS like REACT, JQUERY to build responsive websites, E-commerce sites, Information Websites, Mobile Apps, and Interactive, user friendly features that drive business growth, which focus on providing the best digital user experience.

I'm interested in freelancing opportunities...

WORK EXPERIENCE

NEOTECH, NEW YORK (REMOTE).

POSITION: ENTRY LEVEL FRONTEND DEVELOPER | Mar. 2018 - Dec. 2019.

• Delivered responsive, cross-browser compatible and accessibility compliant websites, achieving 50% faster load time than industry average.

 Produced stunning visual elements of web applications by translating UI/UX design wireframes into code while producing high quality, reusable markup using HTML and CSS.

U-PATH, NEW YORK CITY METROPOLITAN AREA (REMOTE)

POSITION: FRONTEND DEVELOPER | Feb. 2020 - Aug. 2021.

- Delivering solid quality digital, web, and mobile solutions and also translating designs/wireframes to high quality responsive HTML and CSS
- Developing cross-browser and cross-device development & testing, with appropriate use of HTML5 and CSS3 in modern, responsive experiences on the web.
- Interacting with product owner and business representatives to determine and satisfy needs.

LAGOS STATE UNIVERSAL BASIC EDUCATION BOARD (SUBEB) MARYLAND, LAGOS.

POSITION: FRONTEND DEVELOPER | Oct. 2021 - present.

- Translating design team's UX wireframes and mockups into responsive, interactive features, using HTML, CSS, Bootstrap and JavaScript.
- Working with agile team to migrate legacy company website to Sass, HTML5 AND GUI.

• Developing and designing Web applications using REACT.

EDUCATION AND CERTIFICATION

YABA COLLEGE OF TECHNOLOGY, LAGOS STATE.

• Higher National Diploma in Computer Engineering | 2017.

GATEWAY POLYTECHNIC SAAPADE, OGUN.

• Ordinary National Diploma in Computer Engineering | 2010.

SKILLS

- HTML || CSS
- BOOTSTRAP
- JAVASCRIPT
- JS Frameworks e.g. react and JQuery
- GIT
- EXPERT IN RESPONSIVE, MOBILE-FIRST DEVELOPMENT
- COMPUTER APPLICATIONS: MS WORD, EXCEL, POWERPOINT AND GOOGLE APPS, ADOBE PHOTOSHOP.

SOFT SKILLS

- Communication with Non-Technical people.
- Communication with Technical people.

- Team Work.
- Time Management.
- Solving Problems.

LANGUAGE

- English.
- Yoruba.